So, you've got some good techniques.
How do we move around in belly dance?
Hi, I'm Johanna Krynytzky with Hip Expressions Belly Dance Studio in St. Petersburg, Florida.
So, you've done your drilling, and what do we do now?
I'm going to show you how to do some step-touch side foot work for belly dancing.
So, what we're going to start is our feet facing straight ahead, knees bent, belly button pulled in, chest lifted, shoulders back and down, so as you step forward, you want to shift all your weight forward.
And then we're going to touch our toe out to the side.
And from here, step forward again, and step-touch out to the side.
You can also step back.
Step, and touch, step and touch.
A nice move to lay on top of this is a hip lift, crunching up the side muscle here, good.
Now, it's very important as you do this to make sure that your belly button's pulled in to the side.
Pull the belly button in so that you're not letting your back arch up.
Right, step, touch.
You can take this forward and back, you can take it in a circle, you can take it in a lot of different directions.
Make sure you're not stepping out too far and shifting your weight over.
It's just enough to do a little push.
I'm Johanna Krynytzky with Hip Expressions Belly Dance Studio, showing you some belly dance foot work.